(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T21:31:02.147489",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
この番組では みんなのリクエストをお待ちしています
In this program, we are waiting for everyone's requests.
素敵な恋のエピソードといっしょにダイヤルをして
Dial in along with a wonderful love story.
ここでおハガキを一通 R.N「恋するウサギ」ちゃん
Here's a postcard from R.N. "Loving Rabbit"-chan.
「なぜ人を好きになるとこんなにも苦しいのでしょうか？」
"Why is it so painful when you fall in love with someone?"
それは心が君のこと 急かして蹴飛ばしているからで
That's because your heart is rushing and kicking you.
シンプルな頭で聞けばいいのさ let's get to your love!
You can just listen with a simple mind, let's get to your love!
キミが胸を焦がすから 夏が熱を帯びていく
You make my chest burn, so summer gets hot.
そして僕は 湊へと 誘うナンバーを届けてあげる
And I will deliver a number that invites you to the shore.
淡い恋の端っこを 決して離さないでなければ
If you never let go of the edge of a faint love,
この夏は 例年より 騒々しい日が続くはずさ
This summer should have noisier days than usual.
少しは参考になったかな？ R.N「恋するウサギ」ちゃん
Was it a little helpful? R.N. "Loving Rabbit"-chan.
そして世界中で叶わぬ恋にお悩みの方
And to those all over the world troubled by unrequited love,
たぶん心は迷っていて 壊れかけたピンボールみたいで
Perhaps your heart is lost, like a broken pinball,
ルールがいつまでも曖昧なまま is game over?
While the rules remain ambiguous forever, is game over?
キミが夢を願うから 今も夢は夢のまま
Because you wish for dreams, dreams remain dreams even now.
大好きだから踏み出せない 大好きだから臆病になる
Can't take a step because I love you too much, become timid because I love you too much.
淡い恋の真ん中を 泳ぎきってみせてよ
Swim right through the middle of a faint love.
可愛すぎるハートを見守っている ミュージック・アワー
Watching over a heart that's too cute, Music Hour.
強い人にはなれそうにもない 揺れてる君でいいよ
It's okay if you're shaking and can't seem to become a strong person.
let's get to your love!
キミが夢を願うから ミュージシャンも張り切って
Because you wish for dreams, the musicians are also enthusiastic.
また今年も 湊には 新しいナンバー溢れていくよ
And this year too, new numbers will overflow onto the shore.
淡い恋の端っこを 決して離さないでなければ
If you never let go of the edge of a faint love,
この夏は 例年より 騒々しい日が続くはずさ
This summer should have noisier days than usual.
thank you for your letter, loving rabbit
探して 世界中で叶わぬ恋に
Searching for a love unfulfilled anywhere in the world,
お悩みの片隅 心は迷い込んで
my troubled heart wanders off into a corner.
壊れかけた瓶みたいなルルが
Like a broken bottle, the rules remain
いつまでも曖昧なまま
ambiguous forevermore.
いつだって終わりは 君が夢を願うから
Whenever it ends, it's because you wish for a dream,
今も夢は 夢のままで
so even now, dreams remain just dreams.
大好きだから踏み出せない
I love you too much to take that step,
大好きだから臆病になる
I love you too much to be brave.
甘い恋の真ん中を 泳ぎ切って見せてよ
Swim right through the middle of this sweet love and show me!
可哀想すぎるハートを 見守ってるミュージックアワー
The music hour watches over this pitiful heart.
強い人には
To strong people,
なれそうにもない
I could never seem to be like them.
揺れてる君でいいよ
It's okay for you to be wavering.
レッツゴー！ 君が夢を願うから
Let's go! Because you wish for a dream,
今も夢は 夢のままで
so even now, dreams remain just dreams.
レッツゴー！ 君が夢を願うから
Let's go! Because you wish for a dream,
ミュージシャンも張り切って
even the musicians are getting fired up,
まだ少しも切なさには 新しいナンバー
and for a bit of melancholy, a brand new number
溢れていくよ 恋の始まりを
overflows—the beginning of love.
決して離さなければ
If we never let it go,
この夏はレイネンより 切ない日が続くはずさ
this summer will surely be filled with bittersweet days.
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
君たち、盛り上がってくれてますかー！？
Are you guys getting hyped up?!
ライブ感、上がってまーす！
The live vibes are rising!
まだまだ美しい重大発表もあるので最後までぶち上げていってくださいねー！
There are still gorgeous major announcements coming, so keep the hype going to the very end!
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi!
セリフ終わった。ローリング一味……
Finished the dialogue. Rolling crew...
だから、皆さん、どうも、どうも！船長の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
So everyone, hello, hello! Thank you so much for coming to Captain's birthday live!
はい、今日はですね、宝鐘マリン、ハッシュタグ #宝鐘マリン生誕祭2021 でいっぱいつぶやいてくださいね！
Yes, today Houshou Marine, please tweet a lot with the hashtag #HoushouMarineBirthday2021!
今日はこの後は、もう怒涛の超超ゲストメドレー！いっぱいゲストが来ますので、もうどんな曲を誰とどんな曲をやるのかちょっとワクワクしながら見ていってくださいね！
After this, we have a relentless, super-duper guest medley! Lots of guests are coming, so please watch and get excited about which songs we'll do with whom!
ぜひぜひいっぱい、どしどしつぶやいてください！ふー、誕生日だ！イェーイ！それではゲストパート行きますよ！チューコー！イェーイ！
Please tweet lots and lots! Woo, it's my birthday! Yay! Now, let's move on to the guest part! Cheers! Yay!
ねえ そこのお嬢さんはここはもうすぐパラダイス 不満げな顔しちゃだめだろ ダメダメ
Hey, young lady there, this place is about to be a paradise! Don't make an unhappy face, no, no!
スマイルがパスポート それがあればモーマンタイ 楽しんでいこうよ バラ色ライフ
A smile is your passport; with that, you'll be fine. Let's enjoy a rosy life!
ほんのちょっと 勇気出して ワンツー ステップ イェーイ！
Gather just a little courage, one, two, step, yeah!
今までの景色とは 明らかに違う 世界
A world so clearly different from the scenery until now.
フルブーストで！ 楽しもうよ！
Full boost! Let's enjoy it!
「1・2・3で happiness world」
"One, two, three for happiness world!"
今だ get a chance だ 夢をつかもう
Now is our chance, let's grasp our dreams!
明日から 紙吹雪 フィーバー
Starting tomorrow, a confetti fever!
想像したことがない 出来事が きっと 待ってるさ
Unimagined events are surely waiting for us.
sing a song で 心躍らせ ポジティブに
Let your heart dance with a song, stay positive,
さあ 面舵いっぱい！ 気持ち晴れ渡る
come on, helm hard to starboard! As feelings clear up,
その瞬間 全速前進だ
at that very moment, full speed ahead!
いつだって 一人じゃない 私たちと一緒に
You're never alone, we are together,
最高に happy な 人生を
wishing you the happiest life possible!
ほらハッピーな人生を イェイ！
Come on, for a happy life, yeah!
眠たい 眠い ずっと ベッドでいたくないね
Sleepy, sleepy, I don't want to stay in bed all day.
無駄じゃない？ 今日は休みなんだし 3、2、1 ファイト！
Isn't it a waste? Today's a day off, so 3, 2, 1, fight!
そんな時はそう 何かやりたいことやってみよう
At times like that, yeah, let's try doing something we want to do.
さあ出かけよう キミの道に秘める欲望
Now let's head out, embracing the desires hidden on your path.
甘いキミに 甘いキリに
To sweet you, to sweet...
宝鐘マリン生誕祭ライブ 2021
[Houshou Marine Birthday Live 2021]
宝鐘マリン 生誕祭ライブ
重大発表あり！ゲスト多数！
[Major announcement! Many guests!]
宝鐘マリン生誕祭ライブ 2021 重大発表あり！ゲスト多数！
Houshou Marine Birthday Live 2021 - Major Announcements & Guests!
君たち！生誕祭ライブ集まってくれてありがとう！
Hey guys! Thank you so much for gathering for my birthday live!
いっぱい趣味を詰め込んだので最後までいっぱい聴いていってくださいね！
I've packed it full of all my hobbies, so please enjoy listening all the way to the end!
盛り上げてくださーい！お願いします！
Get hyped up! Please!
この番組ではみんなの
In this program, everyone's
リクエストをお待ちしています
requests are always welcome.
素敵な恋のエピソードと一緒にダイヤルをして
Dialing in together with a wonderful love episode,
ここで おハガキを一通
Here is a postcard,
ラジオネーム「恋するウサギ」ちゃん
Radio name: 'In Love Rabbit'-chan.
「なぜ人を好きになるとこんなにも苦しいのでしょうか？」
"'Why is it so painful when you fall in love?'"
それは心が君のこと急かして飛び跳ねているからで
That's because your heart is rushing and leaping for you,
シンプルな頭で聞けばいいのさ
So just keep your mind simple and listen—
let's get to your love!
キミが胸を焦すから夏が熱を帯びてく
Your chest burns, so summer gains heat,
そして僕は岬へと誘うナンバーを届けてあげる
And I'll deliver a tempting number to the cape for you.
淡い恋の端っこを決して離さなければ
If we never let go of the edge of this fleeting love,
この夏は例年より騒々しい日が続くはずさ
This summer is bound to be noisier than usual.
少しは参考になったかな？ラジオネーム「恋するウサギ」ちゃん
Was that helpful at all? Radio name: 'In Love Rabbit'-chan.
そして世界中で お悩みの方
And to everyone in the world troubled with worries,
たぶん心は迷っていて壊れかけたピンボールみたいで
Perhaps your heart is lost, like a broken pinball,
ルールがいつまでも曖昧なまま is game over?
And the rules remain ambiguous forever—is game over?
キミが夢を願うから今も夢は夢のまま
You wish for a dream, so the dream remains a dream,
大好きだから踏み出せない大好きだから臆病になる
Because I love you so much I can't take a step, because I love you so much I become cowardly.
淡い恋の真ん中を泳ぎ切ってみせてよ
Swim right through the middle of this fleeting love!
可愛いすぎるハートを持っているミュージックアワー
Holding a much too cute heart—Music Hour!
強い人にはなれそうにもない揺れてる君でいいよ
You don't have to try and be strong, it's okay to be a shaking you.
let's get to your love!
キミが夢を願うからミュージシャンも張り切って
You wish for a dream, so musicians are fired up too,
また今年も岬には新しいナンバー溢れていくよ
And this year too, new numbers overflow at the cape.
淡い恋の端っこを決して離さなければ
If we never let go of the edge of this fleeting love,
この夏は例年より騒々しい日が続くはずさ
This summer is bound to be noisier than usual.
ラジオネーム「M」くんから届いたダイレクション
Direction received from radio name "M"-kun:
「そして世界中でかなわぬ恋に
"And for an impossible love in this world,"
お悩みの方 たぶん心は迷っていて
To those with worries, perhaps your heart is lost,
壊れかけたピンボールみたいなルールが
Like the rules of a broken pinball,
いつまでも曖昧なまま いつでもお前は
Always remaining ambiguous, always you—
キミが夢を願うから 今も夢は夢のまま
You wish for a dream, so the dream remains a dream,
大好きだから踏み出せない 大好きだから臆病になる
Because I love you so much I can't take a step, because I love you so much I become cowardly.
淡い恋の真ん中を泳ぎ切ってみせてよ
Swim right through the middle of this fleeting love!
可愛いすぎるハートを持っている ミュージックアワー
Holding a much too cute heart—Music Hour!
強い人にはなれそうにもない 揺れてる君でいいよ
You don't have to try and be strong, it's okay to be a shaking you.
let's get to your love!
キミが夢を願うから ミュージシャンも張り切って
You wish for a dream, so musicians are fired up too,
また今年も岬には 新しいナンバー溢れていくよ
And this year too, new numbers overflow at the cape.
淡い恋の端っこを決して離さなければ
If we never let go of the edge of this fleeting love,
この夏は例年より騒々しい日が続くはずさ
This summer is bound to be noisier than usual.
強い人にはなれそうにもない
You don't seem like you could become strong,
揺れてる君でいいよ
It's okay to be a shaking you.
let's get to your love!
キミが夢を願うから ミュージシャンも張り切って
You wish for a dream, so musicians are fired up too,
また今年も岬には 新しいナンバー溢れていくよ
And this year too, new numbers overflow at the cape.
淡い恋の端っこを決して離さなければ
If we never let go of the edge of this fleeting love,
この夏は例年より騒々しい日が続くはずさ
This summer is bound to be noisier than usual.
キミが夢を願うから ミュージシャンも張り切って
You wish for a dream, so musicians are fired up too,
また今年も岬には 新しいナンバー溢れていくよ
And this year too, new numbers overflow at the cape.
淡い恋の端っこを決して離さなければ
If we never let go of the edge of this fleeting love,
この夏は例年より騒々しい日が続くはずさ
This summer is bound to be noisier than usual.
let's get to your love!
君たち！盛り上がってくれてますかー！？
Hey guys! Are you getting hyped up?!
ライブも盛り上がってますかー！？
Is the live getting hyped up too?!
まだまだ素敵な重大発表もあるので最後までぶち上げていってくださいねー！
There are still wonderful major announcements coming up, so please keep raising the hype till the very end!
宝鐘海賊団 ラヴィング・イッツ・ミー！
Houshou Pirates, Loving It's Me!
はーい！というわけで皆さん！
Hi there! So everyone,
どうもどうも！船長の誕生日ライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
hello hello! Thank you so much for coming to the captain's birthday live!
はい、今日はですね、宝鐘マリン、
Yes, today,
ハッシュタグ宝鐘マリン生誕祭2021で
with the hashtag Houshou Marine Birthday 2021,
いっぱい呟いてください！
please tweet a lot!
いっぱいスクショとかしてくださいね、感想待ってます！
Take plenty of screenshots too, I'm waiting for your impressions!
今日はですね、この後はもう怒涛の超超ゲストメドレー、いっぱいゲストが来ますので、
Today, after this, we have a relentless stream of super-duper guest medleys with lots of guests coming,
もうどんな曲を、誰とどんな曲をやるのかちょっとワクワクしながら
so please watch with excitement to see what songs and with whom we'll be performing!
見ていてくださいね！ぜひぜひいっぱい、どしどし呟いてください！
Please tweet a lot and eagerly!
うー！
Woo!
誕生日だ！
It's my birthday!
イェーイ！
Yay!
それじゃあゲストパートいきますよー！
Well then, let's go to the guest part!
しゅっこうー！イェーイ！
Setting sail! Yay!
（1、2、3、hey、イェー！）
(1, 2, 3, hey, yeah!)
ねえ そこ の お嬢さん ここ は
Hey there, young lady,
もうすぐ パラダイス
this is almost paradise,
不満 げ な 顔 し ちゃ ダメ だ よ ダメ ダメ
Don't make such a dissatisfied face, no, no!
スマイル が パスポート それ が あれ ば モーマンタイ
A smile is your passport, with that you'll be just fine!
楽しん で いこう よ バラ色 ライフ
Let's go enjoy a rose-colored life!
ほんの ちょっと 勇気 出し て ワンツー ステップ イェイ ！
Just muster a little courage, one-two step, yeah!
今 まで の 景色 と は 明らか に 異なる 世界
A world completely different from the scenery until now,
フル ブースト で ！ 楽しもう よ ！
full boost! Let's enjoy it!
「 1 . 2 . 3 で happiness world 」
1, 2, 3 for happiness world
今 だ get a chance だ 夢 を つかもう
Now is the time, get a chance, grasp your dreams!
明日 から 紙吹雪 フィーバー
Starting tomorrow, a confetti fever!
想像 し た こと ない 出来事 が きっと 待っ てる さ
Events you never imagined are surely waiting for you!
sing a song で 心 踊ら せ ポジティブ に さあ 面舵 いっぱい ！
Make your heart dance with a song, positively, full speed ahead!
気持ち 晴れ渡る その 瞬間 全速前進 だ
That moment when your feelings clear up, full speed ahead!
いつだって 一人 じゃ ない 私たち と 一緒 に
You're never alone, together with us,
最高 に happy な 人生 を …
towards a most happy life...
ああ 寝 てい たい 眠い ずっと ベッド で 出たく ない
Ah, I want to sleep, so sleepy, always in bed, don't want to come out.
ねえ 無駄 じゃ ない ？ 今日 は 休み な ん だ 睡魔 fight
Hey, isn't that a waste? Today is a day off, fight the sleepiness!
そーゆー とき は そう 何 か やりたい こと やっ て みよう よ 消化 し て こう 君 の 内 に 秘める 欲望
At times like that, let's try doing something you want to do! Digest and express the desires hidden within you!
思い切り 声 を 出し て スリーチュウワンイェイ ！
Shout out loud at the top of your lungs, three-two-one, yeah!
恥ずかしい 気持ち と は 今 すぐ に バイバイ さ
Say goodbye right now to those embarrassing feelings!
エンジン 点火 ！ はじけよーよー ！ 「 1 . 2 . 3 で happiness world 」
Ignite the engine! Let's burst with energy! 1, 2, 3 for happiness world
進め going my way 立ち止まら ず に
Move forward, going my way, without stopping,
未来 へ の ドア 叩け コンコン
knock on the door to the future, knock knock!
1 秒 も 無駄 に は でき ない よ もっと さらけ出せ
You can't waste even a single second, reveal yourself more!
it 's a party ハイテンション で 帆 を 上げろ お宝 へ 出航 ！
It's a party, raise the sails with high tension, set sail for treasure!
後悔 し たく ない その 想い が 追い風 に なる 困っ たら 思い出し て 私たち が いる から
That feeling of not wanting to regret will become a tailwind. If you're in trouble, remember that we are here,
最高 に happy な 運命 を …
toward a most happy destiny...
年が年中it's show time 来るもの拒まないit's all right
All year round it's show time, welcoming all comers, it's all right!
バイブスは最高潮ー！ですのでみんなでoh yeah！両手を上げましょう万歳まだまだこれでももの足りない
The vibes are at their peak, so everyone, oh yeah! Raise both hands, banzai! Still, even this isn't enough,
内気なそこの君こっちおいでよ古今東西老若男女楽しいことが一番でしょ
you shy person over there, come over here! Past and present, east and west, old and young, having fun is the best!
少しタガを外してみましょうようこそワンダーランド
Let's loosen our restraints a bit, welcome to wonderland!
寝から寝ず一触即発！車も混雑キッズonline！
From sleeping to sleepless, instantaneous explosion! Cars jammed, kids online!
パフォーマンスは最高潮！せーのでみんなで oh yeah!
Performance is at its peak, on the count of three, everyone, oh yeah!
予定をあけましょうバンザーイまだまだこれでももの足りない
Clear your schedules, banzai! Still, even this isn't enough,
鬱屈したそこの君好調いいいでここんとこないのお腹空んよ
you gloomy person over there, in great shape? Lately I've been feeling hungry!
楽しいことが一番でしょ少しタガを外してみましょうようこそワンダーランド
Having fun is the best! Let's loosen our restraints a bit, welcome to wonderland!
今日も一歩一歩踏み出せばきっと人生の経験値GETCHU！
If you take it step by step today too, you'll surely get life's experience points!
ふとした何気ないことだって多分笑えるさきっとね笑えるさきっとね笑えるさ
Even casual, trivial things will probably make you smile, surely make you smile!
今 だ get a chance だ 夢 を つかもう
Now is the time, get a chance, grasp your dreams!
明日 から 紙吹雪 フィーバー
Starting tomorrow, a confetti fever!
想像 し た こと ない 出来事 が きっと 待っ てる さ
Events you never imagined are surely waiting for you!
Please kiss my boy
hold me baby
sweet little love boy
yeah!!
新曲で心おどらせ
Let your heart dance to the new song!
ポジティブにさ
Stay positive,
思い切りいっぱい気持ち晴れわたるその瞬間
and feel your spirits soar wide open!
全速全進だ! いつだって一人じゃない
Full speed ahead! You're never alone.
私たちと一緒にさぁここへハッピーな人生を Yeh!
Come here together with us for a happy life, Yeh!
みんなでハッピーな人生を Yeh!
Everyone live a happy life, Yeh!
キスあげるね今年最初のドキドキは
I'll give you a kiss, my very first pounding heart,
キミの腕の中で溢れてポロリこぼれた涙さくらんぼもっとぎゅっとずっと知ってて
overflowing in your arms, cherry-bo, hold me tight!
すきすきすき...
I love you, I love you, I love you...
まだまだかなキミのハートちょっとスパイシー
Is your heart still a little spicy?
ちょっとおやよおやよまちきれないこのままじゃもっとぎゅっとずっと知ってて
Wait, I can't wait anymore, hold me tight!
澄ました顔でキレていじけて戸惑うフリは嫌だよ
Putting on a straight face, sulking, acting confused,
何気なくふんわり手と手をまわして緑道に近づく
holding hands and approaching the path.
本当はずっと好きだったのナイショだねあげて小さな胸が震えてる抱きしめられたら壊れちゃうよ
The truth is I've loved you, if you hug me I'll break.
心を澄ましてポロリこぼれた涙溢れちゃう大人になるための痛みかな
Clearing my heart, overflowing tears spill out.
キミに触れられた甘酸まてクキースはちょっとだけ待ってね
Cookies touched by you, wait just a little longer.
すきすきすきやだやだやだよそ見は嫌だ夢中でいて
I love you! I hate when you look away, be obsessed!
はらりはらりはらわたくしはまだ子供なんだもんでもキミの余裕こそっと胸の奥にそるよ
Falling cherry blossoms, I'm a kid, but your composure slips in.
そんな私すぱっと忘れさせてね優しいキスでなんだかねきゅんとしたの最初だよ
Let me forget with a gentle kiss, my heart went kyun!
あれれね唇がもう触れているキミの睫毛がひとみに映るこの胸の痛みはやけに上昇気流だけの手当
Our lips are touching, your eyelashes reflected in my eyes.
ちょっとかなり幸せことり受け止まる瞬間に壊れそうな心と怪我が赤く弾けたわふしさくらんぼキミとずっとつながってて
A bit too happy, fragile heart bursting red, stay connected.
お神様この唇は彼と出会うために生まれてきたのですね
Oh God, were these lips born just to meet him?
キス私た顔で切れてとまどうふりはやだよ
Acting confused with my face is annoying.
何気なくふんわり手と手をまわして緑道に近づくだってねこんなの初めてなんだもんナイショだよやったね
Approaching hand in hand, because it's my first time, yay!
あれれでおかしいのこの時々はキミの腕の中で溢れこぼれた涙さくらんぼもっとぎゅっとずっと知ってて
Overflowing tears in your arms, cherry-bo, hold me tight.
あれれで声がグルリ回りまわって不輪は夢がごちかぜまかせてずっと待ってた恋は止まらないだからずっと話さないで
Voices spinning around, let the breeze blow, the love won't stop.
すきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきすきっキュー
I love you, I love you... kyuu!
あい うえ おかし した
A, E, O, sweets, down
かき くっきー こんにゃく なに も
Persimmon, cookie, konjac, and nothing at all
さしすせそ ソフトクリーム ごぞうろっぷ で いこう
Sashi, su, se, so, soft-serve, let's go with all five organs!
タッチ ついて とれてきた なにぬねのりしお
Touch, followed and caught, na ni nu ne, salted seaweed
はひふへ ほっと パい と みんなで ぬくぬく
Ha, hi, fu, he, hot pie, everyone nice and cozy
ショートケーキ ふわ り
Shortcake, fluffy...
キャンディ ペロペロ
Candy, licked and licked
チョコレート かわ で
Chocolate on the wrapper...
わたし が もんた
I saw it!
アイスクリーム と プリン の うしろ で
Behind the ice cream and pudding,
カスタード は たぬき
Custard is a tanuki.
ふたり の ランデブー
The two of them rendezvous,
カフェイン サンデー アンコ も ハッピー
Caffeine sunday, sweet bean is happy too!
ほうき に こりーん
Corin on a broomstick,
こくま も ドロップ
Little bear and drops,
タプ ケーキ から いちご あめ まで
From tart cake to strawberry candy,
国境 なき スイーツ 仲良く なる よ
Borderless sweets, becoming good friends!
こーんな よりー 夢見て ごらん
Dream of something even more than this!
キャンディ みたいに くっつこー おーっ！ おっぱい も ぶらんぶらん
Let's stick together like candy, oh! Breasts swinging back and forth,
ヨーグルト ラリルーレ の オール 気分 は ときめき と キス を
Yogurt's rari-ru-re all, feeling thrilled with a kiss,
あい うえ おかし した かき くっきー こんにゃく なに も
A, E, O, sweets, down, persimmon, cookie, konjac, nothing at all
さしすせそ ソフトクリーム ごぞうろっぷ で いこう
Sashi, su, se, so, soft-serve, let's go with all five organs!
のんびり はや で 焼き塗り あぶって おにぎり コロコロ
Leisurely and quick, roast, paint, sear, rice balls rolling,
ともだち ほかほか もみじ まんじゅう と
Friends nice and warm, with maple manju,
アンパン お月様 わらぬきに はじまり
Anpan, the moon, starting with cotton candy,
わらぬきに おわる ふび
ending with cotton candy, hufi!
ラリルーレ みつめて ごらん
Rari-ru-re, look closely,
あまくて 苦い 夕焼け は
Sweet and bitter sunset,
タッチ ついて とれてきた なにぬねのりしお
Touch, followed and caught, na ni nu ne, salted seaweed,
はひふへ ほっと パい と みんなで ぬくぬく
Ha, hi, fu, he, hot pie, everyone nice and cozy,
パリルーレ もぶらんぶらん
Pari-ru-re, moburan-buran,
ヨーグルト ラリルーレ の オール 気分 は ときめき と キス を
Yogurt's rari-ru-re all, feeling thrilled with a kiss,
あい うえ おかし した
A, E, O, sweets, down,
かき くっきー こんにゃく なに も
persimmon, cookie, konjac, nothing at all,
さしすせそ ソフトクリーム ごぞうろっぷ で いこう
sashi, su, se, so, soft-serve, let's go with all five organs!
ラリルーレ の オール 気分 は ときめき と キス を
Rari-ru-re all, feeling thrilled with a kiss,
あい うえ おかし した かき くっきー こんにゃく なに も
A, E, O, sweets, down, persimmon, cookie, konjac, nothing at all,
さしすせそ ソフトクリーム ごぞうろっぷ で いこう
sashi, su, se, so, soft-serve, let's go with all five organs!
ちゅるぴーる はふる ぼむしゅわ
Churu-piru, fluffy bomb shuwa,
たぬき ぱい しゅくるーむ ばなな ぜりー ばばろあ
tanuki pie, choux cream, banana, jelly, bavarois,
ぜりー ばばろあ わたぬき かたけきばのく へんわた ぬきわたぬき
jelly, bavarois, cotton candy, katakeki,
わたぬき ぱたけきば のく へんわた ぬきわたぬき わたわったぬき
cotton candy, cotton candy, cotton candy...
わたぬき と ごはん
Cotton candy and rice,
わたぬき と おやつ
cotton candy and snacks,
わたぬき と 肉まん
cotton candy and meat bun,
わたぬき と ペキンだっく
cotton candy and Peking duck,
みつめめ わたぬき
gazing eyes, cotton candy,
わたぬき シロップ
cotton candy syrup,
ほにょき わたぬき
honyoki cotton candy,
あまり おたのしどん
quite a fun don!
こんがり 思い出汁 の はちみつ
Golden dashi honey,
みたに とろける あい うえ おかし した
melting in sight, A, E, O, sweets, down
かき くっきー こんにゃく なに も
persimmon, cookie, konjac, nothing at all,
さしすせそ ソフトクリーム ごぞうろっぷ で いこう
sashi, su, se, so, soft-serve, let's go with all five organs!
タッチ ついて とれてきた なにぬねのりしお
Touch, followed and caught, na ni nu ne, salted seaweed,
はひふへ ほっと パい と みんなで ぬくぬく
Ha, hi, fu, he, hot pie, everyone nice and cozy,
パリルーレ もぶらんぶらん ヨーグルト ラリルーレ の オール
Pari-ru-re moburan-buran, yogurt's rari-ru-re all,
気分 は ときめき と キス を
feeling thrilled with a kiss,
わたぬき の あまびと わたぬき の にばり
cotton candy's sweet person, cotton candy's nibari,
わたぬき の さみ て すきすき ラブ コモン
cotton candy's samite, suki-suki love common,
ごーん こんがり 思い出汁 の はちみつ
golden dashi honey,
みたに とろける あい うえ おかし した
melting in sight, A, E, O, sweets, down,
かき くっきー こんにゃく なに も
persimmon, cookie, konjac, nothing at all,
さしすせそ ソフトクリーム
sashi, su, se, so, soft-serve!
背番号1の すごい奴が相手
My opponent's an amazing guy wearing the #1 jersey
フラミンゴみたい ひょいと一本足で
Standing on one leg like a flamingo
スーパースターのお出ましに
For the arrival of a superstar
ベンチのサインは敬遠だけど
The bench gave the sign to walk him, but...
何度負けたって
No matter how many times I lose,
ずっと待ってるんだタイミング
I've been waiting for the right moment.
目指すのはあのスターダム
Aiming for that stardom!
Get Chance! アンビリーバブル
Get Chance! Unbelievable!
働くバチみたい ぶんぶん
Working like bees, buzz buzz,
毎日毎日 決まったルーティンつまらない
Every single day, the same routine is boring.
イケた高級カー Vroom Vroom
A cool luxury car, Vroom Vroom!
バーチャルじゃなくていつかリアルでRide
Not just virtual, someday riding in real life!
誰にも期待されてないけど
No one expects anything from me, but
Stand up!
ネバーネバー give up give up 全部全部ぜんぶちょうだい
Never never give up, give me everything!
短いライフサイクル 一か八かでダイブ
A short life cycle, dive on a whim!
何度負けたって
No matter how many times I lose,
ずっと待ってるんだタイミング
I've been waiting for the right moment.
目指すのはあのスターダム
Aiming for that stardom!
Get Chance!! アンビリーバブル
Get Chance!! Unbelievable!
来たる同窓会 Blah Blah
The upcoming reunion, Blah Blah,
マウント取り合いばっかでつまらない
Just competing for social status, so boring.
あの子ブランドバックぶらぶら
That girl swinging her brand-name bag,
自分を着飾るよりも中身で勝負
Rather than dressing up, win with substance!
誰にも期待されてないけど
No one expects anything from me, but
頭ぐるぐるネガティブ
Head spinning round with negativity,
自分にしかきっとできないこと
Something only you can surely do!
Stand up!
ネバーネバー give up give up 全部全部ぜんぶちょうだい
Never never give up, give me everything!
短いライフサイクル 一か八かでダイブ
A short life cycle, dive on a whim!
何度負けたって
No matter how many times I lose,
ずっと待ってるんだタイミング
I've been waiting for the right moment.
目指すのはあのスターダム
Aiming for that stardom!
Get Chance!! アンビリーバブル
Get Chance!! Unbelievable!
終わらないこのストーリー 止まらない最後まで
This unending story, won't stop till the end!
背番号51の すごいヤツが笑う
Number 51, an amazing guy laughs,
おちょうしちゃん投げてみろと ヤツが笑う
Daring me to throw, that guy laughs.
しばらくお似付けさようなら
For a while, farewell to chasing,
でっかい相手をしとめるまでは ちょっとお預け
Until we take down a huge opponent, put on hold!
さああと駆け抜ける
Come on, keep running through,
最高のチャンス スリルの瞬間よ
The greatest chance, the moment of thrill!
熱い視線が 絡み合ったら
When passionate gazes intertwine,
白い火花が パチパチ 心をメロメロ燃えそう
White sparks crackle, heart melting and burning!
私ピンクのサウスポー
I'm a pink southpaw!
キリキリ舞いよ 魔球は魔球は ハリケーン
Spinning around, the magic pitch is a hurricane!
でっかい相手をしとめるまでは ちょっとお預け
Until taking down a huge opponent, put on hold!
さああと駆け抜ける
Come on, keep running through,
最高のチャンス スリルの瞬間よ
The greatest chance, the moment of thrill!
熱い視線が 絡み合ったら
When passionate gazes intertwine,
白い火花が パチパチ 心をメロメロ燃えそう
White sparks crackle, heart melting and burning!
私ピンクのサウスポー
I'm a pink southpaw!
キリキリ舞いよ 魔球は魔球は ハリケーン
Spinning around, the magic pitch is a hurricane!
でっかい相手をしとめるまでは ちょっとお預け
Until taking down a huge opponent, put on hold!
さああと駆け抜ける
Come on, keep running through,
最高のチャンス スリルの瞬間よ
The greatest chance, the moment of thrill!
熱い視線が 絡み合ったら
When passionate gazes intertwine,
白い火花が パチパチ 心をメロメロ燃えそう
White sparks crackle, heart melting and burning!
さあ眠眠打破 昼夜逆転 VOX AC30W
Now, wake up and break sleep, day-night reversal, VOX AC30W
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイが バンド仲間にやっほー
A subculture boy with a Telecaster says hello to his bandmates
アルバイトはネクラモード 対バンにはATフィールド
Part-time job in gloomy mode, AT field for joint bands
“人見知り”宣言で逃げる気か boy
Planning to run away with a "social anxiety" declaration, boy?
ゆーて お坊ちゃんお嬢ちゃん
You say, pampered rich kids,
お金も才能も なまじあるだけ厄介でやんす
Money and talent, having them halfway is just troublesome
boys be ambitious... like this old man
長い前髪 君誰の信者
Long bangs, whose follower are you?
信者 信者 勘違いすんな 祖教はオマエだ
Follower, make no mistake, the cult founder is you!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール かき鳴らす エレクトリックギターは don't stop!
Roki rock-n-roll, strumming the electric guitar, don't stop!
さあ 君のすべてを 暴き出してみせろよ
Come on, expose everything about yourself!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール さあ 日進月歩
Roki rock-n-roll, now making daily progress!
いい曲書いてる？ 動員ふえてる？
Writing good songs? Increasing attendance?
「知名度あるけど 人気はそんなにないから 色々大変ですね。」
You have some fame, but not much popularity, it's tough.
はっきり言うなよ 匿名アイコン
Don't say it so clearly, anonymous icon!
はっきり見せない 写実のアイコン
Don't show it clearly, realistic icon!
いい歳こいて 自意識過剰 boy
Acting your age, self-conscious boy
ぶっちぎれんどんだけ賢くあざとくやったって
No matter how brilliantly and shrewdly you do it,
10年後にメイクは落ちてんだよ
10 years later your makeup will have faded!
boys be ambitious... like this old man
生き抜くためだ キメろ take a "selfy"
To survive, take a selfie!
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにとな！
Don't you dare die on me, to each other!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール 薄っぺらいラブソングでもいい don't stop!
Roki rock-n-roll, even a shallow love song is fine!
さあ 目の前のあなたのその子を 撃ち抜いてみせろよ
Come on, try to shoot through that girl right in front of you!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール お茶を濁してちゃ満足できない
Roki rock-n-roll, can't be satisfied beating around the bush!
スタジオに運ばれたスロートコートは プレッシャーでいっぱい
Throat coat brought to the studio is full of pressure!
「実は昨日から風邪で声が出ません」
"Actually I've had a cold since yesterday and can't speak"
は！？ は！？ は！？ は！？ はぁ…
Huh!? Huh!? Huh!? Huh!? Ha...
寝言は寝て言え ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー
Talk in your sleep when you're sleeping, baby!
ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー
Baby, baby, baby, baby, baby, baby!
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにとな！
Don't you dare die on me, to each other!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール かき鳴らす エレクトリックギターは don't stop!
Roki rock-n-roll, strumming the electric guitar, don't stop!
さあ 君のすべてを 暴き出してみせろよ
Come on, expose everything about yourself!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki rock-n-roll!
死ぬんじゃねえぞ
Don't you dare die on me!
死にたくなえのは お互い様！
Not wanting to die is mutual!
ロキロキのロックロックロー
Roki Roki Rock'n Rock'n Roll
テレキャスター背負った バンド仲間に入り浸りでもいいの？
With a Telecaster, hanging out with bandmates, is that fine?
そう？そう？そう？そう？ 自分の前じゃのっこうちつけて見せろよ
Really? Really? Really? Really? Show it off right in front of me!
煽って見せろよ
Provoke me and show me!
ロキロキのロックロックロー
Roki Roki Rock'n Rock'n Roll
お上品に過ごしてじゃ 満足できない？
Living a refined life, is that not enough?
最初に運ばれたスロート 言葉はアンニュイ、シンプルプレッシャーでいっぱい
Carried first, a sore throat, words full of ennui and simple pressure!
セツナを昨日のことから かき消された最後でもさ
Even if the fleeting moment of yesterday's affairs is erased at the very end,
さあ 君のすべてを 暴き出してみせろよ
Come on, expose everything about yourself!
寝言は寝て言えベイビー
Say your sleep-talk in your sleep, baby!
ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー ベイビー
Baby, baby, baby, baby!
死ぬんじゃねえぞ お互いにさ
Don't you dare die, both of us!
ロキロキのロックロックロー
Roki Roki Rock'n Rock'n Roll
日ならずフレデリックギターを そうそうそうそう
Day in and day out playing Frederic guitars, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
君のすべてを さらけ出してみせろよ
Lay bare everything about yourself!
ロキロキのロックロックロー
Roki Roki Rock'n Rock'n Roll
死ぬんじゃねえぞ 死ぬんじゃねえぞ 死にたかねえのはお互いさま
Don't you dare die, neither of us wants to die!
Smile・Sweet・Sister・Sadistic Surprise・Service・We are スティーレ!!
Smile, Sweet, Sister, Sadistic, Surprise, Service, We are StiLe!!
さあ 扉を開けて 未知なるパラダイス 体験しよう
Now, open the door and let's experience a paradise unknown!
おいでやおいでYOU そう君を待つのは 不思議なオアシス
Come on over, YOU! Yes, waiting for you is a mysterious oasis.
ちょっぴりスパイス
Just a little spice!
ぐーるんぐーるん かき混ぜちゃうんだ ぐーるんぐーるん 当店自慢のゼイバー
Round and round, stirring it up, round and round, our shop's proud flavor!
サービスサービス ご褒美タイム はまてなし心込めて
Service, service, reward time, heartfelt hospitality!
ウェルカムチュウマイ 私たちと一緒に めくるめくワンダーデイリー夢
Welcome, chu-mai! Together with us, experience a dazzling wonder daily dream.
愛情マシマシ 煩悩ナデナデ 誠心誠意つとめます
Love multiplied, worldly desires petted, we sincerely serve you!
せい一杯れば はい!
Give it your all, yes!
みのげんきチャージに 一役買えるかな こういう感じも 悪くないでしょ
Can we play a part in charging your energy? Isn't a vibe like this pretty nice too?
恋の感じも 愛の感じも 意外と悪くないでしょ
The feeling of love and affection is surprisingly not bad at all, right?
ボナペティ ブレンドしたい キミにキュンキュンキュン ハートにバッチバッチバッチ
Bon Appétit, I want to blend! Kyun-kyun-kyun for you, bang-bang-bang to your heart!
ボナペティ ブレンドしたい お口に合いますか
Bon Appétit, I want to blend! Does it suit your taste?
お口に合えば いいな
I hope it suits your taste!
ボナペティ ボナペティ ボナペティ 戦うボンバーアイ
Bon Appétit, Bon Appétit, Bon Appétit, fighting bomber eye!
ちょっと長ぐほほ笑いながらも いつだって重要は斜め上
Smiling a bit long, yet importance is always diagonally above!
そんじゃ一回本当の私は シークレットモードで影響中
So for once, the real me is influencing in secret mode!
ぐるんぐるん かき混ぜてもっと 君仕様のフレーバー サービスサービス 極上タイム
Round and round, mix it more, a flavor made just for you! Service, supreme time!
やしとは かくあるべき
That's how it ought to be!
ウェルカムチュウマイ 私たちのお店に 万事のよーこそ
Welcome, chu-mai! Welcome to our shop for all matters!
おかえり待ってた リピートうれしいな 店員一同歓迎いたします
We waited for your return, so happy for the repeat! All staff welcome you!
キミのお疲れ様にぴったりのレシピで一度カンゲイ
With a recipe perfect for your fatigue, a warm welcome once again!
キミのお疲れ様に ピターリのレシピで
With a recipe tailored to your fatigue!
そういうのどうかな? あゆのもありかな? やんちゃんdeもらえてるかな?
How about that? Is this okay too? Can we get you to behave?
Smile・Sweet・Sister・Sadistic Surprise・Service・We are スティーレ!!
Smile, Sweet, Sister, Sadistic, Surprise, Service, We are StiLe!!
ざぁ、扉を開けて
Open the door now,
奇怪なパラダイス
To a bizarre paradise,
怖がらずにおいで　おいで
Don't be afraid, come on, come on.
さあ、いつもの毎日に
Now, in your usual everyday life
日溜まりと遊びがほら　溢れ出すから
Sunlight and fun come spilling out,
煮詰まってるのえいっ！
Simmering over, eit!
生意気　不意打ち
Cocky, sudden strike,
私たちと一緒に行こうね　クレイジー
Let's go together, it's crazy.
愛情　マシマシ
Affection, extra portions,
束縛はでられない
You can't escape confinement.
精神　誠意つとめて
Do your absolute best with sincerity,
イエス！　君の元気チャージに
Yes! To charge up your energy
いつだって帰るから
I'll always return.
恋の感じも　愛の感じも　意外と
Whether it's love or affection, surprisingly
悪くないでしょ？　ボウノボウノ　ラブレンド
Not bad, right? Bow-and-arrow love blend
さあ君にキュンキュンキュン
Now, for you, kyun kyun kyun
鳩りパンパンパン　ボウノボウノ　ラブレンド
Hato-ri punch punch punch, love blend
お口に合いますか
Does it suit your taste?
赤身　効いたぜ（ねえ？）
Red meat, hit the spot, right?
お口に合いますように
Hoping it suits your taste.
白い雪のプリンセスは
[Song: The White Snow Princess]
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall,
世界で一番可愛いのはやめてよ
Stop calling me the fairest in the world.
棘のような視線迫る　優しいふりした彼女が
Prickly glares close in, she who acted so kind
素敵な晩餐もてなした　そっと口に含むと
Served a wonderful meal, as I gently took a bite—
咽び泣くんだ
Sobbing away.
薄れていく石の中で
Within the fading stone,
夢を見てる
I am dreaming.
いつかのおとぎ話　時間が止まる
An old fairy tale where time stands still.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss,
白い棺から連れ出すように　突き刺す憎しみはドラマチックな事情
Like leading me out of a white coffin. Piercing hatred is a dramatic affair,
祈っても王子様はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, the prince isn't here yet.
願っても君はまだ来ない
Even if I wish, you still haven't come.
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん　ネクタイ任せや頬に挨拶するから
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall, since I leave my necktie to you and greet your cheek,
嫉妬を買われてしまった　7人の小人はいるけれど
I ended up drawing jealousy. Though there are seven dwarves,
助ける素振り　知らん振りで
With gestures to help, feigning ignorance,
そっと首を掴まれ
My throat is gently grabbed.
一粒の涙さえも拭えなくて
Unable to even wipe away a single tear,
呼吸もままならない　視界失った
Unable to even breathe, I lost my sight.
消えそうだから　早く駆け付けて欲しいの
I'm about to vanish, so I want you to hurry over.
訳は聞かないで　応えられない
Don't ask me why, I can't answer.
望まない憎まれは深い愛の二乗
Unwanted hatred is the square of deep love.
もうすぐでいなくなるのかな
Will I be gone very soon?
途切れていく命の音
The sound of life is fading away.
毒リンゴを食した少女のように　眠りにつく
I fall asleep like a girl who ate a poisoned apple.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの　命の音
Please, wake me up with a kiss, the sound of life
くるみ割りを食した少女のように　眠りに就く
I fall asleep like a girl who cracked the walnut.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss,
胸の中の声届きますか
Can the voice in my chest reach you?
階段を登ったらドアを開けるだけで見つかるよ
Just climb the stairs and open the door, and you'll find me.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss,
白い棺から連れ出すように　突き刺す憎しみは
Like leading me out of a white coffin, piercing hatred is...
たとえ君が何処にいても
Even if you are somewhere,
必ず僕がさ、迎えに行こう
I'll definitely go pick you up.
大人になってもきっとふたりで
Even when we grow up, surely the two of us
たくさんの思い出をいっっぱい作りに出かけよう
will go out to make tons of memories together!
どれだけ君のそばにだって
No matter how close I am to you,
心は果てしなく遠い宇宙にいるようで
my heart feels as if it's in a distant universe.
星の数ほどのたったひとつ ぼくらの出逢いはきっと偶然じゃない
Out of all the stars, our one and only meeting surely wasn't a coincidence.
言葉が愛を叫ぼうとしている
Words are trying to cry out love.
細胞のすべてが君を求めてんだ
Every single one of my cells is longing for you.
万事 まじ 快調！
Everything is seriously smooth!
(はい 言っちゃいましょう！)
(Yes, let's say it!)
キミは Best Best Friend!
You are my Best Best Friend!
ちょっと ふざけてみたら
If I try joking around a bit,
もっと ふざけ返してくる
you joke right back even more!
居心地いーし アラシない
It feels so comfortable, no storms here.
イヤなことあったって そこーゆー忘れちゃうんだ
Even if bad things happen, we forget them just like that!
いつだって24時間 一緒でも問題ない！ まるで双子か親子かクローンさいほー
Always 24/7 together, no problem! We're practically twins, parent and child, or clones!
これじゃ恋愛する必要とかなくななくなーい? それとはこのことは全く全く別問題!!
Don't we have no need to fall in love at all? But that and this are totally, completely separate issues!!
ケンカしちゃったときも かなり凹んだときも
Even when we fight, even when we're quite depressed,
ひとりでありたいよなときも ふと気づけば近くにいる しなもろもろとー
even when I want to be alone, before I knew it you're right nearby, and all that stuff~
キミと一緒なら 時計100倍速! 楽しいな 楽しすぎるんだ さすが最強Friend!
If I'm with you, the clock runs 100x faster! It's so fun, way too fun, as expected of my strongest Friend!
Hey! なんみなのよ やばいシンクロ感!
Hey! What's with this dangerous sense of synchronicity!
いつも大騒ぎ かなりご近所迷惑
Always making a huge fuss, quite a nuisance to the neighborhood.
今何時? えっねぇ ヨロレイヒ-
What time is it now? Huh, hey, yoroleihi~
想像以上! なんというか最高! あーだこーだ言ってても 友達わっしょい!
Beyond imagination! What you'd call the absolute best! Even saying this and that, friendship, hooray!
上々 友情!
Top-notch friendship!
万事 まじ 快調!
Everything is seriously smooth!
おんなじテレビ見てて メールで実況中継
Watching the same TV show, doing live commentary via email.
CM入れれば 電話Time 遠くにいるときでも
When commercials come on, phone time, even when we're far apart,
近くに感じてるんだ よろしく ガンガンいきましょう!
I feel you close by, let's go full throttle!
やばい 弁当忘れた カンパして! やだよ命のみなもと 焼きそばパン
Oh no, forgot my bento, spot me some! No way, the source of life is yakisoba bread!
ちょっと友達なのに しょぼくない? それとはこのことは全く全く別問題!!
Isn't that a bit lame for friends? But that and this are totally, completely separate issues!!
だって 冗談の裏 ラブ ゴリラ なんじゃ その生きもの もう飽きた まじか
Because behind the jokes, love gorilla? What's with that creature? Already bored of it, seriously?
ヨロレイヒ- 意味わかんないし それどーしよ 想定以上!
Yoroleihi~ I don't get the meaning, what should we do about that, beyond imagination!
なんというか最高! あんごだこだいってても 友達わっしょい! 上々 友情!
What you'd call the absolute best! Even saying this and that, friendship, hooray! Top-notch friendship!
万事 まじ 快調!
Everything is seriously smooth!
マリフレのじょーじょーゆーじょー 2番をお聞きください。
Marine & Flare's top-notch friendship, please listen to the second verse.
おんなじテレビ見てて チャンネルで実況中継
Watching the same TV show, doing live commentary on the channel...
CM入れば電話Time
When commercials come on, phone time,
遠くにいるときでも 近くに感じてるんだ よろしく ガンガンいきましょう!
even when we're far apart, I feel you close by, let's go full throttle!
やばい弁当忘れた カンパして! やだよ命のみなもと 焼きそばパン
Oh no, forgot my bento, spot me some! No way, the source of life is yakisoba bread!
ちょっと友達なのに しょぼくない?
Isn't that a bit lame for friends?
それとはこのことは全く全く別問題!!
But that and this are totally, completely separate issues!!
変な気は使わない 恋人なんか知らない
We don't stand on ceremony, don't know anything about lovers.
でも傷つけたりしない 神様まじありがと ゲットできたまぶだち
But we don't hurt each other either. Seriously thank you God, I got a true buddy!
やったおっしゃよマリフレ 最高潮 涙が出るくらい 笑い疲れちゃうんだ
Yay, hooray, MariFare at peak climax! Laughing until tears come out, getting exhausted from laughing.
何しようか何をもしましょうか ひとりよりLet's go!
What should we do, what should we say? Better than being alone, let's go!
なんないんだって冗談の裏 並ぶゴリラ なんただその生きもの
Nothin' like that, behind the jokes, lining up gorillas, what's with that creature?
もう飽きたまじかよろレイヒ 意味わかんないし それどーしよ 想定以上!
Already bored, seriously, yoroleihi~ I don't get the meaning, what should we do about that, beyond imagination!
なんというか最高! あんごだこだいってても 友達わっしょい! 上々 友情!
What you'd call the absolute best! Even saying this and that, friendship, hooray! Top-notch friendship!
万事 まじ 快調! (Hey!)
Everything is seriously smooth! (Hey!)
そう友達とずっと楽しく思ってた
I always thought it would be fun staying friends forever.
でもでもやっぱり言えないや Because...
But still, I just can't say it, Because...
はいっチャイましょ 君はベストフレンド! (Bright!)
Let's just go with it, you're my best friend! (Bright!)
ちょっと ふざけてみたら もっと ふざけ返してくる (Shine!)
If I try joking around a bit, you joke right back even more! (Shine!)
居心地い-し アラシない (Lan Lan Lan)
It feels so comfortable, no storms here (Lan Lan Lan).
イヤなことあったって そこーゆー忘れちゃうんだ (Why)
Even if bad things happen, we forget them just like that! (Why)
いつだって24時間 一緒でも問題ない (Fine)
Always 24/7 together, no problem! (Fine)
まるで双子か親子かクローンさいほー (Lan Lan Lan)
We're practically twins, parent and child, or clones! (Lan Lan Lan)
これじゃ恋愛する必要とかなくななくなーい?
Don't we have no need to fall in love at all?
それとはこのことは全く全く別問題!! (Fight)
But that and this are totally, completely separate issues!! (Fight)
ケンカしちゃったときも かなり凹んだときも (Down)
Even when we fight, even when we're quite depressed (Down),
ひとりでありたいよなときも ふと気づけば近くにいる しなもろもろとー (Shock)
even when I want to be alone, before I knew it you're right nearby, and all that stuff~ (Shock)
キミと一緒なら 時計100倍速! 楽しいな 楽しすぎるんだ さすが最強Friend!
If I'm with you, the clock runs 100x faster! It's so fun, way too fun, as expected of my strongest Friend!
Hey! なんみなのよ やばいシンクロ感! いつも大騒ぎ かなりご近所迷惑
Hey! What's with this dangerous sense of synchronicity! Always making a huge fuss, quite a nuisance to the neighborhood.
今何時? えっねぇ ヨロレイヒ- 想像以上! なんというか最高!
What time is it now? Huh, hey, yoroleihi~ Beyond imagination! What you'd call the absolute best!
あーだこーだ言ってても 友達わっしょい! 上々 友情!
Even saying this and that, friendship, hooray! Top-notch friendship!
万事 まじ 快調!
Everything is seriously smooth!
ハロー！ニィハオ！こんにちは！
Hello! Nǐ hǎo! Konnichiwa!
ボンジュール！グーテンタク！アロハ！
Bonjour! Guten tag! Aloha!
「ザップ～ン」 「ザップ～ン」
"Zap~n!" "Zap~n!"
小さな頃に憧れた
Ever since I was little, I dreamed of
冒険劇 夢見るアクアのヒロイン
an adventure story, Aqua's heroine.
何でもなれると信じてた
Believing I could become anything,
神様も見ていた 「不思議ー？」
even God was watching. "Isn't it strange?"
海の流れ流れゆく
The ocean current flows and flows,
時の早さのせいで
because of how fast time flies.
忘れかけた奇跡を もう一度信じられたら
If I can believe in that forgotten miracle once more,
響く波のメロディ
the melody of the waves echoes out.
嬉しい気持ち いつでも wavy
Feeling happy, feeling good, always wavy.
優しさに包まれた街
This town is wrapped in kindness,
迷子の心はほったらかせない
we'll never leave a lost child behind.
星の光射す deep blue town
Starlight shines on the deep blue town.
ハロー！ニィハオ！こんにちは！
Hello! Nǐ hǎo! Konnichiwa!
ボンジュール！グーテンタク！アロハ！
Bonjour! Guten tag! Aloha!
「ザップ～ン」「ザップ～ン」
"Zap~n!" "Zap~n!"
小さな頃と変わらない
I haven't changed since I was little,
溢れる泡の数だけ生まれるスマイル
smiling as much as the bubbling foam.
昨日の喧嘩した友達も
The friend I fought with yesterday
明日には笑うよ
will smile with me tomorrow.
海の故郷身を寄せ
The sea's homeland draws our bodies close,
目を閉じ感じよう
let's close our eyes and feel it.
暗闇に響く歌
When I can feel the song echoing in the darkness,
優しく感じられたら
diving deep into my dreams.
深く夢にダイブ
(deep dive into dreams)
激しい愛しい心のままに
With a fierce and lovely heart,
笑顔で溢れている街
this town is overflowing with smiles.
海いっぱいの愛を届けたが
I wanted to deliver all the ocean's love,
伝わっていくよ deep inside
and it's getting across, deep inside.
海の心 ウオ心
The heart of the sea and the heart of a fish,
繋がる心をアイニー
connected hearts—wǒ ài nǐ.
忘れないで奇跡を
Don't forget the miracle,
君の側で感じるさ
you can feel it right by your side.
届け水のリズム
Deliver the rhythm of the water,
響く波のメロディ
ring out, melody of the waves!
踊れ歌え舞い上がるまで
Dance, sing, until you soar!
海より深い愛の街
A town of love deeper than the sea,
揺れる触れるその柔らかさ
I want to express my thanks
ありがとうを伝えたい
for your swaying, touching softness.
嬉しい気持ち いつでも wavy
Feeling happy, feeling good, always wavy.
優しさに包まれた街
This town is wrapped in kindness,
迷子の心はほったらかせない
we'll never leave a lost child behind.
星の光射す deep blue town
Starlight shines on the deep blue town.
ハロー！ニィハオ！こんにちは！
Hello! Nǐ hǎo! Konnichiwa!
ボンジュール！グーテンタク！アロハ！
Bonjour! Guten tag! Aloha!
「ザップ～ン」「ザップ～ン」
"Zap~n!" "Zap~n!"
女々しくて 女々しくて 女々しくて辛いよ
Memeshikute, memeshikute, memeshikute tsurai yo
「女々しくて」
[Song: Memeshikute]
僕の事をからかったの?
Did you make fun of me?
あんなに好きと言ったのに
Even though you said you loved me so much,
奴のどこを気に入ったの?
what did you like about that guy?
僕はもういらない?
Do you not need me anymore?
君と手をつなぎ踊りたい
I want to hold your hand and dance
たくさんの人ごみの中で
in the middle of a crowded place,
君の笑顔だけが輝いて
where only your smile shines bright.
愛されたいねきっと見過ごした
I wanted to be loved, surely missing
君のシグナルもう一度
your signal once again.
気まぐれかな? でも構わない
Is it a whim? But I don't care,
君と居たいから
because I want to be with you.
女々しくて 女々しくて
Memeshikute, memeshikute,
光を浴びて
bathing in the light,
女々しくて 女々しくて
memeshikute, memeshikute,
恋の歌歌って
sing a love song.
女々しくて 女々しくて 辛いよ
Memeshikute, memeshikute, it's so painful.
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge？
Make it skip a beat with rouge?
いけますよ～！
We can do it!
ねえ、言ったよね？ 年齢なんて関係ないってさ
Hey, you said it, right? That age doesn't matter at all!
そういうめんどくさいのも 含めて愛してくれているって
And that you'd love even those troublesome parts of me, right?
ねえねえ、言ったよね？ 言ってない？
Hey hey, did you say it? Or did you not?
ふーん、そういうこというんだ。
Hmm, so that's how it is.
まかせて！魔法で若返り ヒミツの素顔はキミにだけ トクベツですよ～！？
Leave it to me! Rejuvenated by magic, my secret bare face is a special treat just for you!
ここにこがれ いつもミスをした
Yearning to be here, I always slipped up.
女の子心 雲のよう
A girl's heart is like a cloud—
惚れた腫れた 狭い心が さ迷っている
infatuated and restless, my narrow heart wanders around.
キュートは正義 美少女無罪
Cute is justice, innocent beautiful girl!
キミの一番目指してヨーソロー！
Aiming to be your number one, yosoro!
本当は自信ないけど頑張っちゃう
Though I'm not really confident, I'll do my best!
きゅっきゅっきゅっきゅん きゅっきゅっきゅっきゅんるん
Kyu-kyu-kyu-kyun, kyu-kyu-kyu-kyun-run,
恋する気持ち17歳 0時になっちゃうわオトナの時間
feeling in love at 17, turning midnight into adult time!
ド・キ・ド・キ・して rouge？
Make it skip a beat with rouge?
まだ早い♡
It's still too early!
俺という星に 落としてやるさ
I'll make you fall onto a star called me.
美しい花には 棘があるんだよ
Beautiful flowers have thorns, you know.
おはよう かわいいね 接しちゃうよ
Good morning, so cute, I'll kiss you.
全然言葉が 思いつかない
No words come to mind at all.
お仕置きが 足りなかったかな
I wonder if the punishment wasn't enough.
そんなに潤んだ瞳で見ても 認知してあげない
Even if you look at me with such watery eyes, I won't acknowledge you.
愛嬌つかなかった キミが欲しい
You didn't show any charm—I want you.
ボクの心 犬のよう
My heart is like a dog.
懐かされたって どうぞかまわない
Even if you tame me, I don't care at all.
キミと入れるなら
If I can be with you,
愛されたいね きっと見過ごした
I want to be loved, surely missing
キミのシグナル もう一度
your signal once more.
気まぐれから でもかまわない
Even if it's just on a whim, I don't mind.
キミといたいから
Because I want to be with you.
餓狼を浴びて
Bathed in starving wolves,
恋の歌うたって
singing a love song,
たどり着いたこの 世界はもう
the world we finally reached is already...
辛いよ
so painful.
一海賊ならYo-Ho! 踊れたけりよYo-Ho!
If you're a pirate, Yo-Ho! If you want to dance, Yo-Ho!
さあ 今波さの もとへ 宝海賊団
Now, heading to the waves, to the Houshou Pirates!
宝鐘海賊団 出航だ！
Houshou Pirates, set sail!
踊るアホに 見るアホイ！
The dancing fools and the watching Ahoy!
全速前進だ！
Full speed ahead!
進め！太陽は燦々 大航海日和だ歌え
Advance! The sun is brilliant, perfect weather for a grand voyage, so sing!
最高のエモーション 波の音に乗せ どんぶらこ海で
The ultimate emotion, riding the sound of the waves on a rocking sea,
GIRLS PARTY 丘で 兄貴はHAPPY
Girls party on the hill, big bro is happy.
空の上は 遠く遠く キラキラ
Above the sky, far, far away, sparkling.
山をくぼろぼろ マイハウスで 夢を見て
Peeking into the mountains, dreaming in my own house,
ああ 神様 いつこのマリンを 本物の海賊にしてください！
Ah, God, please make this Marine a real pirate someday!
声を上げて さあ出航だ 我ら宝鐘海賊団
Raise your voices, now set sail, we are the Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に 旗を上げ この海をジャックしちゃお！
Compass in hand, raise the flag and let's jack this ocean!
夜空 続いておいで と共にYo-Ho Yo-Ho 叫ぼう ああ 最高の日々
Night sky, follow along together, Yo-Ho, Yo-Ho, let's shout! Ah, the best days,
ようこそ 我が船へ
Welcome to my ship!
踊るアホに 見るアホイ！
The dancing fools and the watching Ahoy!
1、2、サンバサンバ 熱く
One, two, samba samba, passionately,
語ろうよファッション 想いを解き放て
let's talk about fashion and set our feelings free!
赤くきらめくファッション 形から入るタイプです 発射準備は前
Glowing red fashion, the type that starts with appearance, preparation to launch is ahead—
走れガチ恋でしゃ 物陰もてねるわ
run with serious love, hiding in the shadows...
ギガギガ ゆやけも照れるわ
Giga giga, even the sunset is shy.
じんわり汗もしたたるいい女 だがしかし
A good woman dripping with gentle sweat, but alas—
ああ 神様 船長はセンシティブだと晩婚されちゃうのですね はにゃ～ん
Ah, God, is it because the captain is sensitive that she'll end up marrying late? Hanyan~
奪われたら取り戻せ それが僕らの海賊団
If it's stolen, take it back—that's our pirate crew!
君たちとならたどり着ける 伝説のエルドラド
With you all, we'll reach the legendary El Dorado.
夜通し騒ぎりゃ 歌おうよ
If we carouse all night, let's sing,
ほう！ほう！ 本当にない あぁ この景色
Ho! Ho! There's really nothing quite like this view!
大切な仲間よ
My precious comrades!
暴れろ！暴れろ！騒げや騒げ！
Rampage! Rampage! Make some noise!
踊れ！アホに見える！踊れ！
Dance! You look like fools, dance!
同じアホなら 踊らにゃ損々！
If we're both fools, you might as well dance!
逆さ奪る 片手に 一撃まっしぐらよ
Aim straight ahead with a reversal in hand!
アホイ！アホイ！アホイ！アホイ！
Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy!
宝鐘マリン！
Houshou Marine!
世界で一番？
The number one in the world?
無邪気 無邪気 無邪気
So innocent, so innocent!
エロガキ！ エロガキ！
Perverted brat! Perverted brat!
バンキューブーン！
Bang-cue boom!
お嬢ちゃん パンツの色は何色…？
Little lady, what color are your panties...?
お宝！ お宝！
Treasure! Treasure!
やばい！ やばい！
Oh no! Oh no!
どうでもすごーい 船長のちょっといいとこ
Whatever's amazing, the Captain's good points...
セクシーに… いやーん MAICING〜！
Sexy... Oh my, MAICING!
抜群の… 立ちゅうの…
Outstanding... standing...
サービス！サービス！萌え萌えキュン♡
Service! Service! Moe moe kyun♡
出会って5秒で… 好き好き好き好き
5 seconds after meeting... love, love!
はぁ…もう、船長は君たちのそんな国に…ねぇ、本当に？
Ha... geez, Captain isn't into such... really?
立てばジタバタ、座ればショー、歩く姿は戦士
Stand and thrash, sit and show, walking like a warrior
夢を見ようこの船で 後悔なんてさせない
Let's dream on this ship, no regrets allowed
君たちのおかげで私は
Thanks to all of you, I can become
船長になれるから
the Captain!
みなさん船長コールで！
Everyone, call the Captain!
エーーーックス！
Hey!
声を上げてさあ執拗だ われらほうしょう海賊団
Raise your voices, persistent are we, Houshou Pirates
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ この海をジャックしちゃおう
With compass and flag, let's jack this ocean!
夜空ついておいでともに 夜空叫ぼう
Follow through the night sky together, let's shout!
最高の日日
The greatest days!
ようこそ我が船へ
Welcome to my ship!
宝の鐘の解読だ
Decoding the treasure bell!
それではいきますよ シュッコー！
Now then, here we go, set sail!
はい、まだ帰らないでくださいよ。ここからは告知とグッズのお知らせです。
Yes, please don't leave yet. Here are announcements and merch info.
ちゃんと最後まで見ないと、にわか一味になってしまうのでしっかりと見ることを。
Make sure to watch till the end or you'll become a casual fan!
まずはお誕生日記念グッズです。初めに紹介するのはこちら！
First up is the birthday merch. The first item to introduce is this!
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
船長とおそろいパーカーです。
It's the Captain matching hoodie.
先日お披露目した船長の新衣装とおそろいのデザインになっていますよ。
The design matches the Captain's new outfit revealed recently.
後ろ側の柄は船長はチェックなんですけど、まあ君たちにチェックを着こなすのは難しいでしょう。手加減して普通の赤にしておきました。
The back pattern is check for me, but it's hard for you to pull off. So I made it plain red.
おしゃれでしょう？部屋着もよし、部屋に配置してマリンが脱ぎ散らかしたと妄想するもよし。
Stylish, right? Great for loungewear or imagining Marine left it scattered.
続いてこちら、船長とおそろいキャップです。
Next is this, the Captain matching cap.
こちらも船長の新衣装とおそろいになっていて、おしゃれな帽子でしょう？
This also matches the new outfit, a stylish hat right?
兎田ママのママのルルドも買うって言っていたので、実質ルルドとおそろいまである。
Usada-mama's mama said she'd buy Lulu too, so it's practically matching with Lulu.
さらにこちら！船長とおそろい缶バッジセット！船長の新衣装についている缶バッジです。
And this! Captain matching pin badge set from her new outfit.
パーカーにつけてもよし、カバンにつけてもよし、好きなとこにさし散らかしてください！
Put them on your hoodie or bag, scatter them wherever you like!
そしてこちら！B2お風呂ポスターです。
And this! B2 bath poster.
これは、お風呂に貼れる撥水ポスターなんですよ。お風呂でマリンに水をぶっかけ放題！こんなことが許されていいのか？
A water-repellent poster for the bath. Unlimited water-splashing on Marine in the bath!
君たちとお風呂、楽しみですよ。うふふ。
Bath time with you guys will be fun. Hehe.
さあ、内容が重たいので全部セットも重たい！
Now, since the contents are heavy, the full set is heavy too!
でも、この重たい全部セットをご購入してくれた君には感謝を込めて、ポストカードに直筆ひとことメッセージを書かせていただきます。
To show gratitude to buyers of the full set, I'll write a handwritten message on a postcard.
こちらは数量限定なのでなくなっちゃったら勘弁してください！なくなっても一応直筆、複製メッセージ入りポストカードも手に入りますよ。
Quantity is limited so forgive me if they run out! You'll still get a duplicate message postcard.
いや、本当はねボイスをつけたかったんですけど、納期のタイミングで声が枯れ散らかしていて取れませんでした……！
Actually I wanted voice clips, but my voice was completely hoarse at delivery time...
でも、豪華さな内容なので喜んでね君たち！えーこちら、22時から概要欄にも記載されているブースで販売開始です。要チェックですよ！
Still, it's luxurious so be happy! Sales start at 22:00 at the BOOTH in the description. Check it out!
続いてのお知らせはこちら！宝鐘マリンねんどろいどご予約受付中！
Next announcement! Houshou Marine Nendoroid pre-orders open!
海賊コートなどいろんなオプションパーツが付属されています。顔パーツを付け替えることで様々なシチュエーションを楽しめますよ！
Includes pirate coat and various options. Swap face parts for various situations!
ポケットに忍ばせて…っちょ、マリン！ついてきちゃダメって言っただろ！
"Keep it in your pocket... hey, Marine! I told you not to follow me!"
みたいにやり取りをすることもできます。
You can even do exchanges like that.
こちらは予約期間中に生産上限数に達した場合、予約受付終了になってしまいます。
Reservations will close if the production cap is reached during the reservation period.
こうなってしまったら手に入らない可能性がかなり高いので、絶対ゲットしないと損損ですよ！
The chances of getting it are very low if that happens, so you'll definitely regret missing out!
本日12時から予約受付開始しておりますので、グッドスマイルカンパニー公式サイトをご確認ください。
Reservations start today at 12:00 PM, so please check the official Good Smile Company website.
最後のお知らせは、こちらです！
The final announcement is right here!
宝鐘マリンPC発売決定！ツクモ様から宝鐘マリン仕様のコラボPCが発売されます！
Houshou Marine PC release decided! A collaboration PC with Houshou Marine specs will be released by Tsukumo!
イラストデザイン・制作、PCデザイン監修は船長の「お母さん」、あかさあい先生！メインデザインは深井涼介先生！
Illustration and PC design supervision are by the captain's "mom", Akasa Ai-sensei! Main design by Ryosuke Fukai!
え、お母さんと深井涼介先生は仲良しらしく、2人のね、ずーっとも絆パワーでデザインされた愛のPCです。
Mom and Ryosuke Fukai-sensei are close, and it's a PC of love designed with their enduring bond.
え、このパソコン何が凄いって、まずね、あかさあい先生描き下ろし壁紙！
What's so amazing about this PC? First, newly drawn wallpaper by Akasa Ai-sensei!
そしてね、船長の配信のオープニングとかを手がけて下さっている天狗ノーズ先生！描き下ろしオリジナルマウスカーソル！
Next, Tengu Nose-sensei, who handles stream openings for the captain! A newly drawn original mouse cursor!
そして、船長のとりおろしパソコン用システムボイス付きなんです！
And it comes with newly recorded PC system voices by the captain!
え、パソコンスペックは小・中・大の3パターンありようですよ！
The PC specs come in three patterns: Small, Medium, and Large!
え、営業部長も船長のマネージャーも全世界求めている一品です！
It's an item that both sales managers and the captain's manager worldwide are after!
え、販売期間は2021年秋から冬を予定しております。ま、どんなに遅くても年内だそうです！
Sales are scheduled for autumn to winter 2021. Well, no matter how late, it'll be within the year!
え、パソコン購入予定の方は、ぜひね、ちょっと今は一旦待って、こちらの購入をご検討していただけないでしょうか！
If you're planning to buy a PC, please hold on for a moment and consider purchasing this one!
ということでね、楽しみがもりだくさんです！これからも宝鐘マリンもよろしくお願いします！しゅっこうー！
So there are tons of things to look forward to! Please continue to support Houshou Marine! Set sail!